

CONTACT

Porto, Portugal

□ +351 91 615 15 65

✓ ricarraf@gmail.com

github.com/ricardojaferreira

in /RicardoAraujoFerreira

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES



TECHNOLOGIES

PlayFramework ● Spring ● Zend
Famework ● Angular ● Apache ● Nginx
● Git ● MySql / MariaDB ● MongoDB

ElasticSearch ● Couchbase ●
 RabbitMQ ● LATEX

LANGUAGES



OPERATING SYSTEMS



ACTIVITIES



See the extended version at https://git.io/fhQUd.

Ricardo Jorge de Araújo Ferreira

Electrical and Computer Science Engineer (M.Sc.)
Student of Master in Informatics and Computing Engineering

SUMMARY

I am currently working has a full stack developer in an Agile (scrum) environment with modern technologies, previleging good quality code and architectures. To learn more about software development, I have started the Master Degree in Informatics and Computing Engineering at Faculdade de Engenharia, I am currently at the 4rd year out of a 5 year program.

EXPERIENCE

• Web Engineer - Fullstack Developer

2018/06 - now

Jumia - Porto Tech Center

Porto, Portugal

- Development of web applications using JAVA and PHP frameworks;
- Analysis and implementation of new software solutions.

• Web Engineer - Fullstack Developer

2018/02 - 2018/06

7Skin, Lda - Ecommerce

Porto, Portugal

- Development of ecommerce solutions using Magento;
- Development of internal software to improve productivity.

• Web Engineer - Fullstack Developer

2014/05 - 2018/02

GravityDemand, Lda - Ecommerce

Penafiel, Portugal

- Development of software for ecommerce and marketing solutions;
- Development and integration with external services (REST and other API's).

• R&D - Engineer

2011/01 - 2011/09

INESC - Institute for System and Computer Engineering

Porto, Portugal

- Research and testing in the power energy field (software and hardware);
- ▶ Validate emerging concepts in Smart-Grids with prototypes and models.

Automation Engineer

2008/08 - 2011/01

Efacec, Sistemas de Engenharia

Maia, Portugal

- Development of control and automation systems;
- Management of large information systems based on UNIX platforms.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Informatics and Computation Engineering Present Faculdade de Eng. da Universidade do Porto Porto, Portugal

■ Currently at the 4rd Year, 2 more to finish the graduation.

▶ .

M.Sc. in Electrical and Computers Engineering
Faculdade de Eng. da Universidade do Porto

Present

Porto, Portugal

- Specialization: Automation and Control Systems
- Thesis: Solar Car Control and development. (17 out of 20)